Shiva Manhar

Full Stack Web Developer

Ootaboo Pvt. Ltd., Raipur

Address: Danganiya Raipur (C.G.), INDIA

Phone : +91 8251832932

Email: shivamanhar@gmail.com

Github: https://github.com/shivamanhar

I am a committed senior web developer with over 6 years of experience, self-motivated data analyst and web developers. A quick learner absorbs new ideas and I can communicate clearly and effectively.

My main interests are Statistical modeling, Predictive analytics, Data visualization, Machine learning and Web development.

I enjoy solving problems in an analytical and logical way and especially using data in order to obtain useful information.

Education and Qualifications

2012 **Master of Computer Application**

Pt. Ravishankar Shukla University, Raipur (C.G.), INDIA

2009 **Bachelor of Computer Application**

Guru Ghashi Das University, Bilaspur(C.G.), INDIA

Current Position

Since 2017 Ootaboo Pvt. Ltd., Raipur

> Web based scheduling platform development, creating data reports based on criteria. website: https://xrosters.com

Past Positions

2015-2017 Bright Future Welfare Society, Raipur

Duties: Web Development using PHP, MySQL, Jquery, Ajax, Codeigniter,

MVC, HMVC, Testing, and Marketing.

Pt. Ravishankar Shukla University, Raipur 2013-2014

Duties: Assistant professor

2010-2011 Navabharat Press, Raipur

Duties: Web Designing, Web page uploading and working Joomla CMS.

Other Skills

- Spoken languages: English (elementary proficiency), Hindi (full professional proficiency)
- Programming Languages: PHP, MySQL, Python, C++ (expert), Java (intermediate), Scala (basic), Jquery, Ajax, moment.js, Codeigniter
- Machine Learning: Classification, Clustering, Regression, Anomaly Detection, Recommendation, Time Series
- Visualization: Matplotlib, Seaborn, Bokeh

Journal Publications

R.D. Nirala, Shiva Manhar "Visual Improvement for Dense foggy & hazy weather images, Usig Contrast enhancement techniques" ISST Jouranal of Electrical & Electronics Engineering Vol. 7 No1 jan – june 2016 pp 53-62. ISSN 0976-7363.